{"tossups": [{"question": "John Cutler attempted to discover a vaccination for this disease through human studies in Sing Sing Prison. Cutler also led an experiment where Juan Jos\u00b4e Ar\u00b4evalo allowed Guatemalans to be infected with this disease. This disease was given to participants in a study that claimed to treat \u201cbad blood\u201d to study its untreated progression, even after the discovery of penicillin. Spirochete bacteria spread, for ten points, what sexually transmitted disease that was given to African-Americans at the Tuskegee Institute?", "answer": "<b> syphilis</b>", "metadata": "Science - Biology"}, {"question": "For ten points, name this quartet of laws signed by John Adams in 1798 that enabled the government to expel foreigners and punish anti-government speech.", "answer": "<b> Alien and Sedition</b> Acts", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {}, {"question": "In one of these conflicts, William Eaton led an expedition to capture Derna, and one ship ran aground by William Bainbridge was burned by the crew of the USS<em> Intrepid</em>. The USS<em> Philadelphia</em> was burned in the first of these conflicts by Stephen Decatur, and Decatur\u2019s capture of the<em> Meshuda</em> during the second of these wars led to peace with Tunis, Tripoli, and Algeria. For ten points, name these early 19th century wars between the United States and a group of North African states.", "answer": "<b> Barbary</b> Wars Page 1", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "A decade after the Prague Spring, a similar event in this city was ended by the punishment of people involved in the April Fifth Incident. One man who ruled from this city was targeted by the never-executed Project 5-7-1. The Fifth Modernization was first posted in this city, where a Goddess of Democracy was erected during a 1989 protest put down by Deng Xiaoping. The Bird\u2019s Nest Arena is located in, for ten points, what site of the 2008 Summer Olympics and Tienanmen Square, the capital of the People\u2019s Republic of China?", "answer": "<b> Beijing</b> (accept<b> Peking</b>)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {}, {"question": "In Nazi concentration camps, this group was identified by a single purple triangle. The 1943<em> Barnette</em> case established that this group could refuse to recite the Pledge of Allegiance. Founded by Charles Taze Russell, this group believes that 144,000 people will enter Heaven and practices a form of shunning known as \u201cdisfellowship.\u201d Proscriptions against military service and blood transfusions are held by, for ten points, what non-Trinitarian Christian sect that publishes<em> The Watchtower</em>?", "answer": "<b> Jehovah\u2019s Witnesses</b> <b>Second Quarter</b> Page 2", "metadata": "Religion - Religion"}, {"question": "The Treaty of Newport was one attempt to end this conflict. The Engagers took part in the Putney debates and were crushed at the battle of Preston during this war. Prince Rupert of the Rhine was decisively defeated at Marston Moor during this conflict, in which Pride\u2019s Purge abolished the Long Parliament. Thomas Fairfax at Naseby opened, for ten points, what 17th century war that pitted Oliver Cromwell and Parliament against the royal forces of King Charles I?", "answer": "<b> English Civil</b> War", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "One side during this conflict conquered Colonia del Sacramento, but was forced to return it at the end of this conflict. The Duc de Villars won the Battle of Friedlingen during this conflict. The forces of Eugene of Savoy and the Duke of Marlborough won the Battle of Blenheim during this conflict. The Treaty of Utrecht ended, for ten points, what war that broke out in 1701 after Philip V became the king of a certain Iberian country?", "answer": "War of the<b> Spanish Succession</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "John Paul Stevens wrote a 2014<em> New York Times</em> editorial calling for the removal of this amendment from the Constitution. George Tucker applauded this amendment\u2019s shift from language in the English Bill of Rights restricting its right to the wealthy, and the phrase \u201cthe People\u201d in this amendment was held to apply to private citizens by Antonin Scalia in the 2008 decision<em> D.C. v. Heller</em>. The NRA holds that this amendment conveys an individual right. For ten points, name this constitutional amendment which bars infringing upon the right of the people to \u201ckeep and bear arms.\u201d", "answer": "<b> 2</b>nd Amendment to the U.S. Constitution", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "During this event, Josefinas Hospital was destroyed by an incendiary bomb. This event was described for the London<em> Times</em> by George Steer. The aftermath of this event, which included eight separate waves progressing from heavy bombs, to machine gun strafing, to firebombs, was interpreted in a chaotic mural-sized artwork that shows a speared horse. For ten points, name this 1937 German bombing of a village during the Spanish Civil War, the subject of a large greyscale painting by Pablo Picasso.", "answer": "bombing of<b> Guernica</b> [gair-NEE-ka]", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Visual Fine Arts"}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "One Superintendent for these workers quarreled with Frederick Law Olmstead and required applicants to be \u201cvery plain looking\u201d and at least 30 years old. Walt Whitman and Louisa May Alcott briefly served in this role. Henry Whitney Bellows led the U.S. Sanitary Commission, which mobilized these people and their supplies. Mary Edwards Walker earned a Medal of Honor for her work in, for ten points, what civilian role, also served during the American Civil War by Elizabeth Blackwell and Clara Barton, who founded the American Red Cross?", "answer": "Union Army<b> nurse</b>s (accept any description of the<b> medical</b> profession, including<b> doctor</b>, <b>surgeon</b>,<b> medic</b>, etc.)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "This leader, who rose to power in 1969 after overthrowing King Idris, was overthrown by the National Transitional Council and killed during the Battle of Sirte during the Arab Spring. For ten points, name this colonel and long-time dictator of Libya.", "answer": "Muammar<b> Gaddafi</b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {"question": "<b>This agency\u2019s first head, retired General Hugh Johnson, advocated for a \u201cblanket code,\u201dand its Section 7a guaranteed the right of labor to collectively bargain. Charles Evans Hughes held that it overstepped the legislature\u2019s Commerce Clause power in the (+) \u201csick chicken\u201d case. Until it was unanimously declared unconstitutional by the Supreme Court in</b><em><b> Schechter Poultry Corp. v. US</b></em><b>, this agency was promoted with a (*) </b> blue eagle and the slogan \u201cWe Do Our Part\u201d. For ten points, name this New Deal administration that removed competition by setting prices and fair standards.", "answer": "<b> NRA</b> (or<b> National Recovery Administration</b>)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b>This empire\u2019s only colonial possession, located in Tianjin, was granted in return for their meager participation in the Eight-Nation Alliance. The \u201cBasic State Act\u201d of this empire supposedly recognized all of its ethnic groups, although the status of languages as (+)</b> <b>\u201ccustomary\u201d was often debated.</b> <b>This empire suffered embarrassingly large losses in the</b> <b>This empire suffered embarrassingly large losses in the</b> <b>Brusilov offensive. A member of the Black (*)</b> <b>Brusilov offensive. A member of the Black (*)</b> Hand assassinated this empire\u2019s Archduke Franz Ferdinand in 1914, provoking the First World War. For ten points, name this dual-monarchy led by the Hapsburg dynasty until its dissolution in 1918.", "answer": "<b> Austria-Hungary</b> (accept<b> Austro-Hungarian</b> Empire, prompt on partial answers)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "<b>This river forms three sides of a rectangular shaped passage in the Ordos Loop and is the northernmost of the rivers whose headwaters are located in the Three Rivers Nature Reserve. In 1642, this river was forcefully flooded to halt a rebellion led by (+) Li Zicheng near the end of the Ming Dynasty, which affected the cities of Xuzhou and Kaifeng. The tendency of this river to flood, carrying (*)</b> sediment from the Loess plateau, gives it the nickname\u201cChina\u2019s Sorrow\u201d. For ten points, name this Chinese river, named for the distinctive color of its silt.", "answer": "<b> Yellow</b> River (or<b> Huang</b> He)", "metadata": "Geography - Geography"}, {"question": "<b>The Lamfalussy process was used to develop the financial regulations used by this group. The third Delors Commission ratified the existence of this entity. The Copenhagen (+) criteria are used to determine eligibility to join this group, and the Schengen Agreement allows for freedom of travel between members of this group. This organization was preceded by the (*) </b> ECSC and the EEC and was formally created by the 1993 Treaty of Maastricht. For ten points, name this organization of countries which includes France, Britain, and Germany.", "answer": "<b> European Union</b> (or<b> EU</b>) Page 9", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "<b>One version of this game was coded for free by intern Wes Cherry. Another version of this game, as taught by Andr\u2019e de Staercke, includes a \u201cDevil\u2019s Six\u201d (+) row. That version of this game was published as an app by former Secretary of Defense Donald Rumsfeld in 2016, was named for Winston Churchill, and uses two (*) </b> decks. The goal of this game is to move all cards from the field and deck onto four foundations, starting with the Aces. Klondike is a popular form of, for ten points, what single-player card game?", "answer": "<b> solitaire</b> (accept<b> Churchill solitaire</b> before mentioned; accept<b> Klondike</b> solitaire before mentioned)", "metadata": "Trash - Trash"}, {"question": "<b>One leader of this country proclaimed \u201cdeath to the EPRP\u201d and smashed bottles filled with blood on the floor. Supporters of Lij Iyasu were defeated at the Battle of Segale in this country. Captured British nationals in this country were freed by the forces of (+) Robert Napier, leading to the suicide of Emperor Tewodros II. This country, which was once ruled by a communist junta known as the (*)</b> Derg, defeated Italian forces at the Battle of Adowa. For ten points, name this African country, once led by Emperors Menelik II and the Rastafarian messiah figure, Haile Selassie [HI-lah se-LAH-see].", "answer": "<b> Ethiopia</b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "<b>This work describes public credit as \u201ca very important source of strength and security,\u201dnoting that \u201ctimely disbursements to prepare for danger frequently prevent much greater disbursements to repel it.\u201d It describes a potential \u201cformal and (+) permanent despotism\u201d\u201con the ruins of Public Liberty,\u201d and it re-states the importance of neutrality in the ongoing war between (*) </b> France and Britain, despite an alliance with France. Foreign alliances and political parties are warned against in, for ten points, what address that opens with a decline to run for a third term as President in 1796?", "answer": "George<b> Washington\u2019s farewell</b> address (accept descriptions)  Page 10", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b>This man sent Ventidius Bassus to fight a Parthian invasion, after which he signed the Treaty of Brundisium to divide power with two other allies. This man supported</b> <b>(+)</b> <b>Herod the Great\u2019s attempts to set up a Roman vassal state in Judaea.</b> <b>Herod the Great\u2019s attempts to set up a Roman vassal state in Judaea.</b> <b>This</b> <b>subject of (*)</b> <b>subject of (*)</b> Cicero\u2019s<em> Philippics</em> defeated Cassius and Brutus at the Battle of Philippi. For Cicero\u2019s<em> Philippics</em> defeated Cassius and Brutus at the Battle of Philippi. For ten points, name this Roman general and member of the Second Triumvirate who was defeated by Octavian and committed suicide in Egypt alongside his lover, Cleopatra.", "answer": "Mark<b> Antony</b> (or Marcus<b> Antonius</b>)", "metadata": "History - Ancient History"}, {}], "bonuses": []}